# Pablo González Carrizo

unmonoqueteclea.github.io | linkedin.com/in/pgonzalezcarrizo | github.com/unmonoqueteclea +34 686899046 | Valencia, Spain | pgonzalezcarrizo@gmail.com

# LEAD SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Software Engineer with 7 years of experience specializing in back-end development and Artificial Intelligence. Proven ability to lead teams in building full-stack applications, designing distributed data pipelines, and deploying complex Machine Learning workflows. Experienced in mentoring junior developers and collaborating with executives to ensure alignment between technical solutions and business objectives.

#### **SKILLS**

Languages: Python, Clojure, JavaScript, HTML/CSS, SQL

Frameworks: Django (Django Rest Framework), Celery, FastAPI, VueJS, Pandas, Tensorflow, Scikit-Learn

**Developer Tools**: AWS, Git, Docker, CI/CD, Github Actions, Emacs, Code Assistant LLMs **Management**: Agile/Scrum, Complex Problem Solving, Team Mentoring & Training

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

# AccuShoot (BigML spin-off), US | Lead Software Engineer

Sep. 2021 – Present

- Led the development of the core back-end architecture using Django, Celery, and Postgres to power all company products for shooters.
- Designed the architecture for AccuShoot LFX, a gamified live-fire training system utilizing thermal cameras for real-time shot detection and scoring.
- Developed a Computer Vision system to analyze shooters' body poses, enhancing performance insights.

#### BigML, US | Full-Stack Engineer

Sep. 2018 – Present

- Led the development of a full-stack framework used in over 10 internal and external distributed applications.
- Contributed to the back-end of a Clojure-based distributed Machine Learning as a Service (MLaaS) platform and the Lisp-based domain-specific language, WhizzML.
- Led and contributed to multiple projects involving the creation of Machine Learning-driven web applications.
- Mentored junior developers, providing them with in-depth knowledge of distributed systems and Machine Learning principles.

#### SolidQ, Spain | Data Platform Specialist

Jan. 2017 - Jul. 2017

• Automated several ETL tasks using SQL Server and SQL Server Integration Services

### **EDUCATION**

# Polytechnic University of Valencia

**University of Alicante** 

Valencia, Spain

Master's Degree in Telecommunications Engineering

2017 - 2019

Degree in Sound and Image in Telecommunications Engineering, Graduated with Honors

Alicante, Spain *2013-2017* 

# PROJECTS

#### valencianow | Python, Streamlit, Tinybird

June 2024 – Present

- Developed a webapp that provides real-time traffic information about the city of Valencia: valencianow.unmonoqueteclea.freemyip.com (self-hosted)
- Automated data collection and transformation pipelines for seamless and efficient data processing.
- Utilized a column-oriented database to collect and manage large volumes of sensor data.
- Open Source: Find the code at github.com/unmonoqueteclea/valencianow

# voilib | Python, FastAPI, SvelteJS, SQLite, Qdrant, Whisper, Docker

Dec. 2022 - Present

- I am the founder and sole developer of voilib.com, a search engine for podcasts.
- Developed a system that collects, transcribes, indexes, and queries podcast episodes, enabling users to find the most relevant fragments based on their prompts.
- Open Source: Find the code at github.com/unmonoqueteclea/voilib